{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following enzyme is used for synthesis of RNA under the direction of DNA?", "opta": "RNA polymerase", "optb": "DNA ligase", "optc": "DNA polymerase", "optd": "RNA ligase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the usual sequence of a Pribnow box?", "opta": "AUAUA", "optb": "TATAAT", "optc": "UUUUU", "optd": "TTGACA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following component of RNA polymerase facilitates the recognition of promoter sequences?", "opta": "a subunit", "optb": "b subunit", "optc": "s subunit", "optd": "c subunit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement defines a replicon?", "opta": "A DNA molecule that encodes pili for conjugation", "optb": "A DNA molecule that is able to replicate and be maintained", "optc": "A DNA template which is used in transcription", "optd": "The enzyme responsible for transposition", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which eukaryotic RNA polymerase makes tRNA's?", "opta": "RNA polymerase 1", "optb": "RNA polymerase 2", "optc": "RNA polymerase 3", "optd": "Any of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The location of first hexameric sequence typically found in pro-karyotic promoters is", "opta": "at the transcription start site", "optb": "approximately 35 bases upstream of the transcription start site", "optc": "approximately 10 bases upstream of the transcription start site", "optd": "approximately 25 bases upstream of the transcription start site", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a product of transcription?", "opta": "mRNA", "optb": "tRNA", "optc": "rRNA", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sigma factor", "opta": "is responsible for recognizing the termination sequence", "optb": "provides the catalytic function of cleaving off pyrophosphates during mRNA synthesis", "optc": "recognizes the promotor", "optd": "accomplishes DNA restriction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The synthesis of mRNA based on a DNA template is called", "opta": "DNA replication", "optb": "transcription", "optc": "translation", "optd": "DNA restriction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Recognition/binding site of RNA polymerase is called", "opta": "receptor", "optb": "promoter", "optc": "facilitator", "optd": "terminator", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following enzyme(s) is/are required for lactose fermentation?", "opta": "Transacetylase", "optb": "\u03b2-galactosidase", "optc": "Galactoside permease", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these catalyzes the synthesis of RNA from a DNA template?", "opta": "DNA gyrase", "optb": "DNA ligase", "optc": "DNA polymerase", "optd": "RNA polymerase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A level of regulation, demonstrated by the termination of transcription if tryptophan is abundant, by the tryptophan operon in E.coli cells is called", "opta": "activation", "optb": "attenuation", "optc": "corepression", "optd": "desiccation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An mRNA transcript of a gene contains", "opta": "a start codon", "optb": "a stop codon", "optc": "a terminator", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following proteins first binds to TATA box during transcription?", "opta": "TF II A", "optb": "TF II D", "optc": "TF II B", "optd": "RNA polymerase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The components found in all prokaryotic transcription terminators is", "opta": "a poly-U region", "optb": "Rho factor", "optc": "a hairpin structure", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A specific __________ factor helps RNA polymerase bind to late promoters and transcribe late genes.", "opta": "sigma", "optb": "beta", "optc": "delta", "optd": "gamma", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}